gotsoccer.com 2019-06-18

# GotSoccer.com

### GotSoccer Privacy Policy

#### Effective Date: September 21, 2018

#### WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS:

Your privacy is very important to us. GotSoccer, LLC and our affiliates (collectively "GotSoccer", "we", "us", "our") value your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By using our websites, services, products, social media sites, support, tools and applications (collectively our "Services"), you signify your consent to our collection and use of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.   
In connection with using our Services, we may collect information from you which can be used to identify you, such as your name, address, email address, phone, date of birth, gender, username and password ("Personal Data"). This Privacy Policy explains what Personal Data about you we collect from you and others, and how we use it. As you use our Services, we want you to be clear how we are using your information and the ways in which you can protect your Personal Data. 

#### Our Privacy Policy explains:

  1. Why We Collect and Use Personal Data
  2. What Personal Data We Collect and How We Collect It
  3. How We Use the Personal Data We Collect
  4. How to Access and Control Your Personal Data

By using our Services, you explicitly consent to the use of Personal Data for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. If at any time you object to any of these uses of Personal Data, you should stop using our Services and notify us that permission for any use of your Personal Data is withdrawn. If you opt-out of the use of your Personal Data, you will not be able to use our Services. 

#### WHY WE COLLECT AND USE PERSONAL DATA:

We use your Personal Data with your consent and in furtherance of our legitimate interests, including providing you with any Services you have requested or authorized. The Personal Data we collect from you and others allows you to use our Services, and for you to register for and log into your GotSoccer Account. We collect and use your Personal Data to provide you the best experience with our Services, and so that you or your child may participate on his or her team, club and association. 

#### WHAT PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT AND HOW WE COLLECT IT:

We may collect Personal Data in the following ways: 

  1. Information You Provide. Many of our Services require you provide your Personal Data, including to register for a GotSoccer Account. When you register, we may ask for personal information, such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, gender, birth date and other personal information necessary for you to participate on your team, club, state association and national organization. You may also provide us Personal Data when you request our Services or report a problem with our Services.
  2. Information Your Team, Club, State or National Association Gives Us About You. GotSoccer may collect and process Personal Data provided by our clients, which may include your team, club, association, state association, national organization, and other similar organizations (collectively "GotSoccer Clients"). These GotSoccer Clients may provide us information about you, with your consent, so that you may use our Services and participate on your team or club. For example, your team's manager, coach or your club may provide us, with your consent, your player information and other Personal Data to register you for a tournament or a league. Your club may authorize your team manager, team coach or other representatives to access your Personal Data for the purposes of administering your team. If a GotSoccer Client provides any of your Personal Data to us, the GotSoccer Client is responsible for providing any notices and/or obtaining any consents necessary from you for us to access and use the Personal Data. We do not control information collection or use practices of GotSoccer Clients. Please contact your team, club, association, state association, national organization, or other organizations regarding their own privacy policies. Once your Personal Data is provided to us by a GotSoccer Client, you may access and control your Personal Data pursuant to the provisions of this Privacy Policy.
  3. Information We Get from Your Use of Our Services. We may collect information about the events and programs that you use and how you use them, such was when you apply for a tournament or register with a club that uses our Services. This information may include: 
    * Device Information - We may collect device-specific information, such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information including phone number.
    * Log Information - When you use our Services or view content provided by GotSoccer, we may automatically collect and store certain information in server logs. This may include details of how you used our service, such as your event attendance; internet protocol addresses (IP addresses); system activity, browser type, the date and time of your request and referring URL; and cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your GotSoccer Account.
    * Unique Application Information - Certain Services including event applications, background checks, player registrations, or programs registration have a unique application number. This number and information about your application may be kept by GotSoccer when you use our Services.
    * Cookies and Anonymous Identifiers - We use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our sites and applications, or use our Services, and this may include sending one or more cookies or anonymous identifiers to your device. We may also use cookies and anonymous identifiers when you interact with Services we offer to our partners, such as advertising services. We use information collected from cookies and other technologies, like pixel tags, to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services. Some of our Services contain widgets, which may be hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. When you use our Services, other companies also collect certain information on you using anonymous identifiers, cookies and the other tracking technologies mentioned above. In this regard, we use Google Analytics to better understand how our customers navigate to and through our websites, how long customers spend visiting our content items and how often they return to visit our websites. You may set your browser to block all cookies; however, it's important to remember that many of our services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.
    * Visitors to Our Websites - When you visit our websites, we may collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is processed in a way that does not identify you. We do not make, and do not allow these service providers to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

#### HOW WE USE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT:

We do not share your Personal Data with any third parties for marketing purposes. We may use, share and disclose information about you, including Personal Data, in the following ways: 

  1. To Communicate with You and Provide You with Our Products and Services. We may use your Personal Data to provide our Services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Services, and for other customer service related purposes.
  2. To Improve Our Services and Tell You About Other Services. We also use your Personal Data to improve and personalize your experience, and to develop new products. In addition, we may use your Personal Data to offer you tailored content - such as giving you offers for third party products and services that we think may be of use to you. Each such marketing communication will also provide you with the option to unsubscribe from such future communication. You may also opt-out of receiving marketing communications from GotSoccer in your GotSoccer Account.
  3. With Our Service Providers. We may share your Personal Data with our affiliates, vendors, consultants and other service providers, who may help us provide and support our Services. These companies may include, for example, our payment processing providers. When you provide payment data to make a purchase of our Services, we will share payment data with banks and other entities that process payment transactions or provide other financial services, and for fraud prevention and credit risk reduction. These service providers agree to only use such information for the purposes for which they have been engaged by GotSoccer, and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  4. With Your Team, Club, State and National Organization. When you use our Services, you expressly authorize GotSoccer to share your Personal Data with your team, club, tournament organizer, and state or national organization (the "Authorized Users") so that they may administer your team's registration, schedule and tournaments. For example, registering to play for a club means you want that club and its authorized users to access your Personal Data so it can place you on a team, register you for a tournament and administer your team.. We only share your Personal Data with the Authorized Users with your consent, or as necessary to provide any product or service you have requested or authorized.
  5. Disclosures for Law Enforcement and Other Purposes. We will share your Personal Data when we have a good faith belief that doing so in necessary to: (1) meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, including to meet any national security or law enforcement requirements; (2) enforce applicable Terms of Use, including investigation of potential violations; (3) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; (4) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of GotSoccer, our users, or the public as required or permitted by law; and (5) in the event that we become involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of our assets, we will ensure that the acquiring organization agrees to protect Personal Data in accordance with the commitments we have made in this Privacy Policy.
  6. Non-Personally Identifiable Information. We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our clients, such U.S. Youth Soccer, state organizations, national organizations, advertisers or connected sites. For example, we may share such non-personally identifiable information to show trends about the general use of our Services.

#### HOW TO ACCESS AND MANAGE YOUR PERSONAL DATA:

You have certain choices available to you when it comes to accessing and managing your Personal Data. The following is a summary of those choices and how to exercise them. 

  1. Access and Changes to Your Personal Data. You can view, update and edit certain types of Personal Data in your GotSoccer Account. Certain information may not be directly changed by you (such as name, gender, and birth date) after certain verification processes (examples include player pass and official roster information). You can view and edit certain preferences, such as which colleges might interest you, using the college recruiting area of your GotSoccer Account. You can also control with whom you share Personal Data with from your GotSoccer account. If your Personal Data changes, you are responsible to notifying us of the changes. Your Personal Data will only be retained for as long as it is required for the purposes for which it was collected. We will give you access to any Personal Data we hold within 30 days of any request for that information by contacting us at: <https://www.gotsoccer.com/privacy_center/>
  2. Deletion of Your Personal Data. In accordance with and as permitted by applicable law and regulations, we will retain your Personal Data only for as long as necessary to provide our Services to you and to maintain your GotSoccer Account. In the event you wish us to delete your Personal Data, you can notify us using the following link: <https://www.gotsoccer.com/privacy_center/> If you request that we delete your Personal Data, you will not be able to use our Services.
  3. Opt-Out of Communications. You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by using the unsubscribe link within each email, updating your email preferences within your GotSoccer Account, or by contacting us as provided below to have your contact information removed from our promotional email list. Even after you opt out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive transactional messages from us regarding our Services.
  4. Cookies. You may also set your browser to block all cookies, including cookies associated with our services, or to indicate when a cookie is being set by us. However, it's important to remember that many of our services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

#### OTHER IMPORTANT PRIVACY INFORMATION:

  1. Information Security - GotSoccer is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Data. We use a variety of security techniques to protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information we hold, including the following protections: (1) we encrypt many of our Services (communication is transmitted using the HTTPS protocol, using industry standard encryption algorithms); (2) we review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems; and (3) we restrict access to your Personal Data to GotSoccer employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information to process it, and who are subject to this Privacy Policy.
  2. Where We Store and Process Personal Data. GotSoccer stores and processes Personal Data on our servers in various locations. We may store and process your Personal Data on a server located outside the country where you live. Regardless of where you live and use our services, you authorize us to transfer, store, and use your information in the United States, United Kingdom or any other country. Regardless of where the Personal Data is stored, we take steps to ensure that the data is processed according to the provisions of this Privacy Policy and the requirements of applicable law. The privacy and data protection laws and rules regarding when government authorities may access data may vary from those in the country in which you live.
  3. Application of Privacy Policy. Our Privacy Policy applies to all the sites, services and applications offered by GotSoccer and its affiliates, but excludes services that have separate privacy policies that do not incorporate this Privacy Policy. For example, clubs (and coaches/administrators authorized by clubs), associations, and state associations may, with your consent, export your Personal Data to comply with obligations from the United States Soccer Federation (USSF), U.S. Youth Soccer (USYS) or other similar organizations. Our Privacy Policy does not extend to data and its use once exported, with your consent, from GotSoccer to your club, association, state association or national association. Please contact your club, association, state organization, USSF, USYS or others regarding their own privacy policies.
  4. Changes to Privacy Policy. We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy, which may change from time to time. We will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Privacy Policy changes).
  5. Third-Party Links. Our website, services and applications may link to other sites that we do not control. In addition, you may have visited our website through a link or a banner advertisement on another site. In such cases, the site you linked from may collect your information. These third-party sites are governed by their own privacy policies. Be sure to review these privacy policies when visiting such sites to see how they collect and use this information. We are not responsible for the content of privacy practices of such third-party sites.
  6. 'Do Not Track' Notifications. Some browsers allow you to automatically notify websites you visit not to track you using a "Do Not Track" signal. There is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Like many websites and online services, we currently do not alter our practices when we receive a "Do Not Track" signal from a visitor's browser.
  7. Children Under 13. GotSoccer?s sites, services and applications are intended for general audiences and are not directed to children under the age of 13. Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use our sites, services or applications. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 13, or other individuals who are not legally able to use our sites, services and applications. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected Personal Data from a child under the age of 13, we will promptly delete it, unless we are legally obligated to retain such data. When you use our Services, you may provide us with Personal Data regarding your minor child. If your minor child is registered with a GotSoccer Client, such organization may provide information to us, with your permission, regarding your child. Contact us if you believe that we have mistakenly or unintentionally collected information from a child under the age of 13. Any parent of a child has the right to review the child?s Personal Data, order its deletion, and refuse to allow further collection or use of the child?s Personal Data using our online contact form at <https://www.gotsoccer.com/privacy_center/>.
  8. Ownership of Your GotSoccer Account - GotSoccer is a Software as a Service (SaaS) company. We own the actual user accounts and have the right to restrict or deny access.
  9. Terms of Use. Your use of our Services is subject to our Terms of Use.

#### EU-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD FRAMEWORK:

  * GotSoccer complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. GotSoccer has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, GotSoccer is potentially liable.
  * GotSoccer is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). In compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles, GotSoccer commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact GotSoccer using our online contact form: <https://www.gotsoccer.com/privacy_center/>
  * GotSoccer has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU Privacy Shield, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint. Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.
  * In accordance with EU-U.S. Privacy Shield principles, EU individuals have the right to access their Personal Data. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Program, and to view GotSoccer's certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

#### CONTACT US:

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at:   
GotSoccer, LLC  
Attn: Privacy Office  
750 Third Street  
Neptune Beach, Florida 32266  
<https://www.gotsoccer.com/privacy_center/>
